A Guide to the Rosenthal Collection of Historical Portraits ca.[1880-1900]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Rosenthal Collection of Historical Portraits ca.[1880-1900]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
99
This collection consists of 346 engravings and lithographs of historical figures.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Albert Rosenthal on August 23, 1938.
Biographical/Historical Information
Max Rosenthal, artist, born in Turck, Russian Poland, November 23, 1833. In 1847 he went to Paris, where he studied lithography, drawing, and painting with M. Thurwanger, with whom he came to Philadelphia, Pa., in 1849, where he completed his studies. He made the chromo-lithographic plates for what is believed to be the first book in the United States fully illustrated by this process, The hunter-naturalist: Romance of sporting; or, Wild scenes and wild hunters by C.W. Webber (Philadelphia: J.W. Bradley, c1851.)
Albert Rosenthal was born in Philadelphia, Pa., on January 30, 1863, the son of the etcher and lithographer Max Rosenthal (1833-1918). His artistic education under his father and at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts was followed some years later by further studies in Europe. In 1892 Rosenthal established a portrait studio in Philadelphia, where he continued to work for the rest of his active career. He died in 1939.
Scope and Content
Portraits, chiefly etchings and lithographs by Max and Albert Rosenthal, of prominent British and American figures in the American Revolution; delegates to the Continental Congresses and Constitutional Convention, United States Presidents, Senators, Congressmen and Justices of the Supreme Court.
Some of the engravings are artist's proofs and many are signed by one of the Rosenthals.
Arrangement
The portraits are arranged alphabetically by surname of the subject and subarranged alphabetically by artist in the case of multiple portraits of a single subject.
Contents List
- Alden, Roger, 1754-1836 n.d., 2 copies (Box-folder 1:1)
- Allen, Andrew, 1740-1825 n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Allen, James, 1744-1811 n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Allen, William, 1704-1780 n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Arnold, Margaret Shippen, 1760-1804 n.d. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Baldwin, Abraham, 1754-1807 n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
  "From a print by J.B. Forest"
- Baldwin, Henry, 1780-1844 1890 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Barbour, Philip Pendleton, 1783-1841 1889 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Baron, Alexander, 1745-1819 n.d. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Barton, Thomas, 1730-1780 n.d. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Bassett, Richard, 1745-1815 n.d. (Box-folder 1:11)
  "From the St. Memin Collection"
- Baylor, George, 1752-1784 1889 (Box-folder 1:12)
  "From the miniature in possession of the family"
- Brady, Joseph P. (Joseph Plunkett), b. 1869 1889 (Box-folder 1:13)
- Bement, Clarence S. (Clarence Sweet), 1843-1923 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Biddle, James, 1731-1797 n.d. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Blair, John, 1732-1800 1890 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Blair, John, 1732-1800 n.d., 3 copies. (Box-folder 1:17)
- Blatchford, Samuel, 1820-1893 1889 (Box-folder 1:18)
- Blount, William, 1749-1800 1888, 2 copies. (Box-folder 1:19)
  "From photograph of original painting furnished by Dr. Thommas Addis Emmett."
- Braddock, Edward, 1695?-1755 1896, 2 copies. (Box-folder 1:20)
  "after H.B. Hall"
- Brewer, David J. (David Josiah), 1837-1910 1890 (Box-folder 1:21)
- Brown, Henry Billings, 1836-1913 1891 (Box-folder 1:22)
- Buchanan, James, 1791-1868 n.d. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Burton, Robert, 1747-1825 n.d., Photographic reproduction. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Butler, Pierce, 1744-1822 1888 (Box-folder 1:25)
  "From a photograph of the miniature furnished by Dr. Thommas Addis Emmett"
- Cadwallader, George n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:26)
- Campbell, John Archibald, General n.d. (Box-folder 1:27)
- Campbell, John Archibald, 1811-1889 1889, 2 copies. (Box-folder 1:28)
- Carroll, Daniel, 1756-1829 1888 (Box-folder 1:29)
- Catron, John, ca. 1786-1865 1889 (Box-folder 1:30)
- Ceracchi, Giuseppe, 1751-1801 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:31)
- Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811 1890 (Box-folder 1:32)
- Chew, Benjamin, 1722-1810 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:33)
- Childs, Cephas Grier, 1793-1871 n.d. (Box-folder 1:34)
- Chovet, Abraham, 1704-1790 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:35)
- Clark, Abraham, 1726-1794 1888 (Box-folder 1:36)
- Clarke, Alured, Sir, 1744 or 5-1832 1885 (Box-folder 1:37)
- Clifford, Nathan, 1803-1881 1890 (Box-folder 1:38)
- Clinton, James, 1736-1812 n.d. (Box-folder 1:39)
  "From the St. Memin Collection."
- Clymer, George, 1739-1813 1888 (Box-folder 1:40)
  "After painting by C.W. Peale." "From the original painting in the Penna. Academy of Fine Arts."
- Cox, James, 1751-1834 n.d. (Box-folder 1:41)
- Cromwell, Oliver, 1599-1658 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:42)
- Curtin, Andrew Gregg, 1815-1894 n.d., Initialed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:43)
- Curtis, Benjamin Robbins, 1809-1874 1889 (Box-folder 1:44)
- Cushing, Thomas, 1725-1788 n.d. (Box-folder 1:45)
- Cushing, William, 1732-1810 1889 (Box-folder 1:46)
- Daniel, Peter V. (Peter Vivian), 1784-1860 1890 (Box-folder 1:47)
- Davie, William Richardson, 1756-1820 1888 (Box-folder 1:48)
  "From a print by Longacre."
- Davis, David, 1815-1886 1889 (Box-folder 1:49)
- Dayton, Jonathan, 1760-1824 n.d. (Box-folder 1:50)
- Decatur, Stephen, 1779-1820 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:51)
- Dent, John H. (John Herbert), 1782-1823 n.d. (Box-folder 1:52)
- Dickinson, John, 1732-1808 1888 (Box-folder 1:53)
  "After painting by C.W. Peale." "From the original painting in Independence Hall."
- Dickinson, Philemon, 1739-1809 n.d. (Box-folder 1:54)
  "After painting by J. Trumbull."
- Duché, Jacob, 1738-1798 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:55)
- Dunlap, William, 1766-1839 n.d. (Box-folder 1:56)
- Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844 n.d. (Box-folder 1:57)
- Duvall, Gabriel, 1752-1844 1888 (Box-folder 1:58)
- Elliot, Andrew, 1728-1797 n.d. (Box-folder 1:59)
- Ellsworth, Oliver, 1745-1807 1888 (Box-folder 1:60)
  "From the original painting in the possession of the family."
- Ellsworth, Oliver, 1745-1807 n.d. (Box-folder 1:61)
- Erskine, William, Sir, 1728-1795 n.d., 2 copies. (Box-folder 1:62)
  "From a print by S. W. Reynolds in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn."
- Evelyn, William Glanville, 1742-1776 n.d. (Box-folder 1:63)
  "From a portrait in the possession of the family."
- Ewing, Samuel, 1776-1825 1887 (Box-folder 1:64)
- Few, William, 1748-1828 1888, 2 copies. (Box-folder 1:65)
  "From the miniature in the possession of the family."
- Field, Stephen Johnson, 1816-1899 1890 (Box-folder 1:66)
- Findley, William, 1741 or 2-1821 n.d. (Box-folder 1:67)
  "From the original painting by C. W. Peale in the City Hall, Phila."
- Fleming, William, 1736-1824 n.d. (Box-folder 1:68)
- Foulke, John, 1757-1796 n.d. (Box-folder 1:69)
  "From the painting in the possession of the College of Physicians of Phila."
- Franklin, William, 1731-1813 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:70)
- Fraser, Simon, 1729-1777 n.d. (Box-folder 1:71)
  "From a print by James Watson in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn."
- Gerry, Elbridge, 1744-1814 1888 (Box-folder 1:72)
  "From the miniature in the possession of the family"
- Gervais, John Lewis, 1741-1798 n.d. (Box-folder 1:73)
- Gibson, John Bannister, 1780-1853 1903, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:74)
  "Daguerreotype by Brady"
- Gilman, Nicholas, 1755-1814 1888 (Box-folder 1:75)
- Girard, Stephen, 1750-1831 n.d. (Box-folder 1:76)
- Glentworth, George, 1735-1792 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:77)
  "Copley pinxit"
- Goodman, John D., 1794-1830 n.d. (Box-folder 1:78)
  "From the original painting in the possession of D. Hayes Agnew M.D. Phila."
- Gordon, Patrick, ca. 1664-1736 n.d., 2 copies. (Box-folder 1:79)
  "From the original painting in the possession of the Historical Society of Penna."
- Gorham, Nathaniel, 1738-1796 n.d. (Box-folder 1:80)
  "From the original painting in the possession of the family"
- Grant, James, 1720-1806 n.d. (Box-folder 1:81)
  "From a print by Kay in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Green, Charles, 1749-1831 n.d. (Box-folder 1:82)
  "From a print of the death of Gen'l. Fraser by Nutter in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Grey, Charles Grey, Earl of, 1729-1807 n.d. (Box-folder 1:83)
  "From a print by Collyer in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804 n.d. (Box-folder 1:84)
  After Weaver?
- Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804 1900, Signed by Max Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:85)
- Hamond, Andrew Snape, Sir, 1738-1828 1888, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:86)
- Hancock, Winfield Scott, 1824-1886 1902, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:87)
  "From photograph by Gutekunst"
- Harlan, John Marshall, 1833-1911 1890 (Box-folder 1:88)
- Harris, George Harris, 1st Baron, 1746-1829 n.d. (Box-folder 1:89)
  "From a print by S. W. Reynolds in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Harrison, Benjamin, ca. 1726-1791 n.d. (Box-folder 1:90)
  "Trial proof. M. R. sc." in Albert Rosenthal's hand.
- Harrison, Robert Hanson, 1745-1790 1889, 2 copies. (Box-folder 1:91)
  "After J. Trumbull"
- Hartranft, John F., 1830-1889 n.d. (Box-folder 1:92)
- Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 1804-1864 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:93)
- Hedge, J. R. 1890 (Box-folder 1:94)
- Henry, Patrick, 1736-1799 1888, 4 copies. (Box-folder 1:95)
- Henry, William, 1729-1786 n.d. (Box-folder 1:96)
- Higginson, Stephen, 1743-1828 n.d. (Box-folder 1:97)
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935 n.d., "no. 6" Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:98)
- Howe, William Howe, Viscount, 1729-1814 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:99)
- Howell, David, 1747-1824 n.d. (Box-folder 1:100)
- Hunt, Ward 1890 (Box-folder 1:101)
- Ingersoll, Jared, 1749-1822 n.d. (Box-folder 1:102)
  "After painting by C. W. Peale" "From the original painting in the possession of Edward Ingersoll, Esq."
- Iredell, James, 1751-1799 n.d. (Box-folder 1:103)
- Jackson, Howell Edmunds, 1832-1895 n.d. (Box-folder 1:104)
- Jackson, William, 1759-1828 1888 (Box-folder 1:105)
  "After painting by J. Trumbull" "From the original painting in the Historical Society of Penna."
- Jay, John, 1745-1829 n.d. (Box-folder 1:106)
- Jay, John, 1745-1829 1887 (Box-folder 1:107)
- Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826 n.d. (Box-folder 1:108)
  "Stuart pinx. Max Rosenthal sc." "The only finished copy of this plate. Albert Rosenthal 8-12-38"
- Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826 1895, 112 of 25; signed artist's proof. Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 1:109)
- Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826 n.d. (Box-folder 1:110)
- Jenifer, Daniel of St. Thomas, 1723-1790 1888 (Box-folder 1:111)
  "After Trumbull" "From photograph of the original painting, furnished by Dr. Thomas Addis Emmett"
- Johnson, Henry, Sir, 1748-1835 n.d. (Box-folder 1:112)
  "From a print by Sangster in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Johnson, Thomas, 1732-1819 1890 (Box-folder 1:113)
- Johnson, William Samuel, 1727-1819 1888 (Box-folder 1:114)
  "From painting by Gilbert Stuart" "From the original painting in Columbia College"
- Jones, Willie, ca. 1741-1801 1889 (Box-folder 1:115)
- Keller, M. W. 1889 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Kenley, J. W. 1890 (Box-folder 2:2)
- King, Rufus, 1755-1827 1888 (Box-folder 2:3)
  "After painting by Trumbull" "From the original painting in the Trumbull Collection, Yale School of Art"
- Kingston, Robert n.d. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Knowlton, Thomas, 1740-1776 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:5)
  After Trumbull?
- Lacy, Horace n.d. (Box-folder 2:6)
- Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834 1901, 3 copies. 2 copies signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:7)
  "From the portrait by C. W. Peale painted for Gen. Washington, owned by Gen. G. W. Custis Lee, Lexington, Va."
- Lafayette, Marie Adrienne de Noailles, marquise de, 1759-1807 1894 (Box-folder 2:8)
  "From a miniature in the possession of the family"
- Lafayette, Marie Adrienne de Noailles, marquise de, 1759-1807 1894, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:9)
- Lamar, L. Q. C. (Lucius Quintus Cincinnatus), 1825-1893 1889 (Box-folder 2:10)
- Langdon, John, 1741-1819 1888 (Box-folder 2:11)
- Lansing, John, 1754-1829 1888 (Box-folder 2:12)
  "From the photograph of the original painting furnished by Dr. Thomas Addis Emmett"
- Laurens, John, 1754-1782 1898 (Box-folder 2:13)
  "From the miniature in the possession of H. L. Laurens, Charleston, S.C." "Edition limited to 50 copies, 15 colored"
- Laurens, John, 1754-1782 1898 (Box-folder 2:14)
- Lawrence, Thomas, 1689-1754 n.d. (Box-folder 2:15)
- Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794 1885, 2 copies. (Box-folder 2:16)
  1 copy with note in Albert Rosenthal's hand: "Richard Henry Lee after Peale (Max Rosenthal sc.) Trial print."
- Lee, Robert E. (Robert Edward), 1807-1870 1902 (Box-folder 2:17)
  On guard sheet: "Etched by Albert Rosenthal after an original photograph furnished by Robert Lee Traylore, Richmond, Va."
- Leib, Michael, 1761-1822 n.d. (Box-folder 2:18)
- Leitch, James n.d. (Box-folder 2:19)
- Balcarres, Alexander Lindsay, Earl of, 1752-1825 n.d. (Box-folder 2:20)
- Livingston, William, 1723-1790 1888 (Box-folder 2:21)
- Logan, Deborah Norris, 1761-1839 1889, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:22)
- Logan, George, 1753-1821 1889 (Box-folder 2:23)
- Tousard, Louis de, 1749-1817 n.d., 2 of the 3 states present. (Box-folder 2:24)
  "In mezzotinto by Max Rosenthal from the engraving in the St. Memin Collection owned by Hampton L. Carson, Esq., Phila. Edition limited to 50 sets in 3 states of the plate. Border designed by engraver."
- Ludlow, George James, 1758-1842 n.d., 2 copies. (Box-folder 2:25)
  "From a print by Nicholls in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- McClurg, James, ca. 1746-1823 1888 (Box-folder 2:26)
  "After painting by Gilbert Stuart" "From photograph of the original painting furnished by Dr. Thomas Addis Emmett"
- McHenry, James, 1753-1816 1888 (Box-folder 2:27)
- McKean, Thomas, 1734-1817 n.d., 2 copies. (Box-folder 2:28)
  "From a print by Tiebout in the possession of the Historical Society of Penna."
- McKenna, J. (Joseph), 1843-1926 n.d. (Box-folder 2:29)
- McLean, John, 1785-1861 1890 (Box-folder 2:30)
- Madison, James, 1751-1836 1888, 2 copies; 1 copy possibly a proof and signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:31)
  "After painting by G. Stuart" "From the original painting in the possession of Thomas Jefferson Coolidge, Boston"
- Mann, William B. (William Benson), 1816-1896 n.d. (Box-folder 2:32)
- Martin, Alexander, 1740-1807 1888, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:33)
- Mason, George, 1725-1792 1888, 3 copies. (Box-folder 2:34)
  "From the painting in the possession of the family"
- Massey, Eyre, 1719-1804 n.d. (Box-folder 2:35)
  "From a print by Van Den Berghe in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Matthews, Stanley, 1824-1889 n.d. (Box-folder 2:36)
- Meade, George Gordon, 1815-1872 n.d. (Box-folder 2:37)
  "M.R." in Albert Rosenthal's hand; possibly a proof.
- Mifflin, Thomas, 1744-1800 1888 (Box-folder 2:38)
  "After painting by Gilbert Stuart" "From the original painting in the possession of Alex. J. Dallas Dixon, Esq., Phila."
- Mitchell, James T. (James Tyndale), 1834-1915 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:39)
- Montrésor, John, 1736-1799 n.d. (Box-folder 2:40)
  "From a portrait in the possession of the family"
- Moore, Alfred, 1755-1810 1889 (Box-folder 2:41)
- Morris, Cadwalader, 1741-1795 1885 (Box-folder 2:42)
- Morris, Robert, 1734-1806 1901, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:43)
  "Gilbert Stuart, pinx."
- Morris, Robert, 1734-1806 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:44)
  "Gilbert Stuart pinxit"
- Morton, Levi P. (Levi Parsons), 1824-1920 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:45)
- Muhlenberg, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1818-1901 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:46)
- Musgrave, Thomas 1885 (Box-folder 2:47)
  "From a print by Facius in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Nash, Stephen G. n.d., Possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:48)
- Neilson, John, 1745-1833 1887 (Box-folder 2:49)
- Nelson, Samuel, 1792-1873 1890 (Box-folder 2:50)
- Nelson, Thomas, 1738-1789 1889, 5 copies; 1 signed by Albert Rosenthal and possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:51)
  "From the painting by Chamberlain in the possession of the family"
- Oswald, Eleazer, 1755-1795 n.d. (Box-folder 2:52)
  "From a print in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn, Esq."
- Page, John, 1744-1808 n.d. (Box-folder 2:53)
- Pakenham, Edward Michael, 1778-1815 1888 (Box-folder 2:54)
  "From a print in the collection of Mr. Clarence S. Bement, Phila."
- Paterson, William, 1745-1806 1888 (Box-folder 2:55)
  "From the painting in the National Museum, Phila."
- Paterson, William, 1745-1806 1890 (Box-folder 2:56)
- Patton, John, 1746-1800 n.d. (Box-folder 2:57)
- Patterson, Robert n.d. (Box-folder 2:58)
- Pellham?, F.? W. 1896 (Box-folder 2:59)
- Penn, John, 1700-1746 n.d. (Box-folder 2:60)
- Penn, John, 1700-1746 n.d. (Box-folder 2:61)
- Penn, William, 1644-1718 1902, 2 copies; both signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:62)
- Phillips, William, 1731?-1781 n.d. (Box-folder 2:63)
  "From a print by V. Green in the collection of C. R. Hildeburn"
- Pinckney, Charles, 1757-1824 1888 (Box-folder 2:64)
  "From photograph of the original painting furnished by Dr. Thomas Addis Emmett"
- Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth, 1746-1825 1888 (Box-folder 2:65)
  "From the original painting in the Trumbull Collection, Yale School of Art"
- Pratt, Matthew, 1734-1805 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:66)
- Prévost, Augustine, ca. 1725-1786 n.d. (Box-folder 2:67)
  "From a drawing by du Simitiere in the possession of Theodore L. Prevost, Esq."
- Price, R. C. 1890 (Box-folder 2:68)
- Putnam, Rufus, 1738-1824 1897 (Box-folder 2:69)
  "Sala Bosworth, pinx." "From the original painting in the Marietta College, Marietta, Ohio"
- Randolph, Edmund, 1753-1813 1888, 2 copies. (Box-folder 2:70)
  "From the original painting in the State House, Richmond, Va."
- Read, George, 1733-1798 1888 (Box-folder 2:71)
- Ridgway, Jacob 1889, Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:72)
  "From the miniature in the Ridgway Library, Philadelphia"
- Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796 n.d. (Box-folder 2:73)
  Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof.
- Robin, abbé, 1750-1794 1888 (Box-folder 2:74)
  "From a rare print in the collection of Mr. Clarence S. Bement, Phila."
- Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:75)
  After Sargent?
- Rosenthal, Albert, 1863-1939 1895, Possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:76)
  "Albert Rosenthal aet 32"
- Rosenthal, Max, 1833-1918 1890, Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:77)
- Ross, George, 1730-1779 n.d. (Box-folder 2:78)
  "B. West pinxit." "From the original painting in the possession of the family"
- Ross, James, 1762-1847 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:79)
  After Sully?
- Rush, Phoebe Anne, 1799-1857 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:80)
  "From the miniature in the Ridgway Library"
- Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813 n.d., "M.R." in Albert Rosenthal's hand. (Box-folder 2:81)
  After Sharples?
- St. Clair, Arthur, 1734-1818 1889 (Box-folder 2:82)
- St. Clair, John, Sir n.d., 2 copies. (Box-folder 2:83)
  "From a miniature by Copley, presented to the Historical Society of Pennsylvania by Dr. Charles Willing."
- Savage, Edward, 1761-1817 1899, 1 of 4 states present; no.14 of 25 sets. (Box-folder 2:84)
  "Twenty five set in four states of the plates printed and subscribed for by ... 14. Charles Roberts"
- Shippen, William, 1712-1801 1897, Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 2:85)
- Shiras, George, 1832-1924 n.d. (Box-folder 2:86)
- Smallwood, William, 1732-1792 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:87)
- Smith, Robert, 1757-1842 n.d. (Box-folder 2:88)
- Smith, William, 1728-1814 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:89)
- Smyth, Alexander, 1765-1830 n.d. (Box-folder 2:90)
- Spaight, Richard Dobbs, 1758-1802 1887?, 2 copies; 1 signed by Albert Rosenthal and possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:91)
  "From the miniature in the possession of the family. From the photograph furnished by Dr. Thomas Addis Emmett."
- Stanhope, Charles Stanhope, Earl, 1753-1816 n.d. (Box-folder 2:92)
- Stewart, Charles, 1729-1800 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:93)
- Story, Joseph, 1779-1845 1890 (Box-folder 2:94)
- Strong, Caleb, 1745-1819 1888 (Box-folder 2:95)
  "After painting by G. Stuart." "From the painting in the possession of the Massachusetts Historical Society"
- Strong, William, 1808-1895 1889 (Box-folder 2:96)
- Swayne, Noah Haynes, 1804-1884 1890 (Box-folder 2:97)
- Taney, Roger Brooke, 1777-1864 1899 (Box-folder 2:98)
- Taylor, Bayard, 1825-1878 n.d., by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:99)
- Temple, John, Sir, 1732-1798 n.d. (Box-folder 2:100)
- Thompson, Smith, 1768-1843 1889 (Box-folder 2:101)
- Thomson, Charles, 1729-1824 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:102)
- Thornton, William, 1759-1828 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 2:103)
  "From the original painting in the U.S. Patent Office"
- Tilghman, Edward, 1750-1815 n.d. (Box-folder 2:104)
- Tilghman, Edward, 1750-1815 n.d. (Box-folder 2:105)
  "From the original in the possession of Edward Tilghman, Esq."
- Tilghman, Matthew, 1718-1790 n.d., 2 copies. (Box-folder 2:106)
- Todd, Thomas, 1765-1826 n.d. (Box-folder 2:107)
- Trimble, Robert, 1777-1828 1889 (Box-folder 2:108)
- Tucker, Thomas Tudor, 1745-1828 n.d. (Box-folder 2:109)
- Vaughan, John, Sir, 1747 or 8 1795 n.d. (Box-folder 3:1)
  "From a print in the collection of Mr. Clarence S. Bement"
- Waldegrave, George Waldegrave, Earl, 1751-1789 n.d., Signed by Max Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:2)
  "From a print by Earlorn in the collection of Mr. Clarence S. Bement"
- Waite, Morrison R. (Morrison Remick), 1816-1888 1890 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Waite, Morrison R. (Morrison Remick), 1816-1888 1887 (Box-folder 3:4)
- Walton, George, 1749 or 50-1804 n.d., Signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:5)
- Walton, George, 1749 or 50-1804 n.d. (Box-folder 3:6)
- Washington, Bushrod, 1762-1829 n.d. (Box-folder 3:7)
  "From an unfinished print by Longacre in the collection of R. C. Davis, Esq., Phila."
- Washington, Bushrod, 1762-1829 1891 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1899, 3 of 4 states present; no.2 of 25 sets; 1 state signed by Max Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:9)
  "Twenty five sets in four states of this plate printed and subscribed for by ... 2. Clarence S. Bement."
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1888, by Albert Rosenthal; possibly a proof. (Box-folder 3:10)
  "Joseph Wright pinxit"
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1897, of 4 states present; no.18 of 25 sets; 1 state signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:11)
  "Twenty five sets in four states of this plate printed and subscribed for by ... 18. Jacob E. Barr."
  " ... from the picture painted from life in 1784 by Charles Willson Peale"
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1897, Signed by Albert Rosenthal; No. 12. (Box-folder 3:12)
  "From the painting by C. W. Peale, 1784, made to the order of the Trustees of the College of New Jersey, now in Nassau Hall, Princeton, N.J."
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1890, Possibly a proof. (Box-folder 3:13)
  "from a painting by C.W. Peale"
- Washington, George, 1732-1799 1899, 1 of 4 states present; no.19 of 25 sets; signed by Albert Rosenthal. (Box-folder 3:14)